<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data science on Samuel Workman</title>
    <link>https://www.samuelworkman.org/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data science on Samuel Workman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.samuelworkman.org/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Four Principles of Data Collection</title>
      <link>https://www.samuelworkman.org/blog/hunter-gatherer-culture-in-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.samuelworkman.org/blog/hunter-gatherer-culture-in-research/</guid>
      <description>I have spent an academic lifetime compiling original data sets, both in my work and as part of broader research teams. In doing so, I have become quite opinionated about the role of data in science, its collection, and its organization. In this post, I detail four principles of data collection and organization useful to any analyst needing to collect data, whether by hand or machine. Often, students, junior scholars, business analysts, and public managers engage in data collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping RStudio Cheatsheets</title>
      <link>https://www.samuelworkman.org/blog/scraping-up-bits-of-helpfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.samuelworkman.org/blog/scraping-up-bits-of-helpfulness/</guid>
      <description>The word “confluence” means the juncture or merging of things, usually rivers. I grew up in West Virginia near the confluence of Gauley River (world-class whitewater for you rafters) and Meadow River (a smallmouth bass fishing haven). The word confluence is also an apt description of how the intellectual currents of my work converge. My work sits at the confluence of statistics, data science, and public policy. Were these rivers, data science would undoubtedly be the smallest.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
